cut-e.com 2019-09-02

# Online Privacy Notice | cut-e

## 

Aon’s Assessment Solutions Online Privacy Notice

 **Data Controller**  
Aon Assessment GmbH (referred to as Aon’s Assessment Solutions)  
Address: Grosser Burstah 18-32, D-20457 Hamburg  
Telephone: +49-40-3250 389-900  
Email: gdpr@cut-e.com

 **Data Protection Officer**  
Dr. Thomas Balzer  
Address: Grosser Burstah 18-32, D-20457 Hamburg  
Telephone: +49-40-3250 389-900  
Email: gdpr@cut-e.com

 **Overview & Scope**

The aim of this Online Privacy Notice (“Notice”) is to provide you with important information about how we process your personal data, particularly important information pursuant to Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“GDPR”). Aon’s Assessment Solutions (“we” “our” or “us”) is committed to protecting the confidentiality, accuracy and integrity of all personal data with our high technical and organisational standards. 

We reserve the right to update and/or modify this Notice at any time.

 **INFORMATION FOR WEBUSERS  **

 **1.     Our Processing**

Below are the different ways in which you may choose to use our website and therefore the ways in which we may process your personal data, including our legal basis for the processing under the GDPR. 

 **1.1 Website use  
Categories of Personal Data: **User technical data.  
 **Purpose of processing:** (i) Technical provision of our site, (ii) Provide information about our services and products, and understand your interests.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** (i) Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is the successful provision of our website, (ii) Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is to provide you with information about products and services we offer, and understand your interests in relation to these.

 **1.2 Contact  
Categories of Personal Data:** User technical data, contact details.  
 **Purpose of processing:** (i) To make contact with you where you have so requested (for example, “Contact us”, “Request a demo”, “Academic Research Portal”), (ii) To allow you to download materials relevant to your interests.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** (i) Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is to contact you and/or provide relevant materials where you have so requested, (ii) Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is in providing you with important or interesting information related to our services.

 **1.3 Interactive Gaming  
Categories of Personal Data:** User technical data, identification information (not required).  
 **Purpose of processing:** To provide you with interactive gaming.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is to provide you with interactive gaming to improve your user experience. 

             **1.4 Careers  
Categories of Personal Data:** User technical data, personal details, employment history.  
 **Purpose of processing:** Facilitating your job application.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** Article 6(1)(b) – your personal data is necessary for entering into any future employment relationship with us ( _not providing your personal data means you will not be able to apply for a position_ ).

 **1.5 scienceBlog  
Categories of Personal Data:** User technical data, contact details.  
 **Purpose of processing:** The provision of our scienceBlog and your interaction with it.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** Article 6(1)(f): Our legitimate interest is to provide you with the information on our scienceBlog, and to allow you to share comments.

 **1.6 Newsletter  
Categories of Personal Data: **User technical data, contact details.  
 **Purpose of processing:** Send you our newsletter/promotional material.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** Article 6(1)(a) - _You are able to withdraw your consent to receiving our newsletter/promotional material at any time.  _

 **2.     Recipients of your Personal Data**

We only share your personal data where necessary for the purpose of the processing.

Aon will be the primary recipient of your personal data. This includes Aon’s subsidiaries and affiliates.

 **Unaffiliated third parties:** We may share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties who perform administrative, marketing, professional or technological support functions for this website. We also share your personal information with third parties who assist us with our job boards, or with whom we have agreements, namely the REXX system.

 **Authoritative bodies:** Aon’s Assessment Solutions may be required to disclose personal information by law or legal process. We reserve the right to contact appropriate authorities when activities that are illegal or violate our policies occur on our website.

 **3.     Transfer to third countries and/or international organisations**

Even if you are located in the European Union, personal data collected whilst you use this website may be processed in a country where the adequacy of that countries data protection laws have not been approved by an adequacy decision of the European Commission. Where we transfer personal data in this manner, we will ensure that any such agreements involving the processing of your personal data will be concluded so that your personal information is protected to an acceptable EU standard under standard EU contractual clauses for the transfer of data, which provide you and your personal data with adequate safeguards. If you would like more information as to how we protect your personal data in these circumstances, please contact our Data Protection Officer with the contact details that we provided above.

 **4.     Storage of your Personal Data **

We only store your personal information for a period reasonable for our purposes of processing and/or for a period of time that is required of us by the law. We do not process your data any longer than we need to. 

If you would like more information about our retention periods, please contact our Data Protection Officer.

 **5.     Cookies**

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your device when you visit our website. Each time you visit, these cookies are returned to us. This allows us to recognize you, for example, or to help you navigate by using the information in the cookies. Cookies cannot be used to launch programs or to transfer viruses to a computer. The reading of cookies is only possible through the web server from which they originated.   
You can also view our website without cookies. To prevent the use of cookies by your internet browser, you may disable the use of cookies through the settings of your internet browser. The help functions of your Internet browser will generally tell you how to deactivate and / or delete cookies in your browser. Please note that disabling / deleting cookies may cause certain features on our site to stop functioning as expected.   
Cookies that we use for certain functions include:  
(1)    Cookies that store certain user preferences (e.g. search or language settings);  
(2)    Cookies that store data to ensure trouble-free playback of video or audio content;   
(3)    Cookies that temporarily store certain user entries;   
(4)    Cookies used to identify or authenticate our users.

We store the cookie data until the end of the term of a particular cookie or until the cookies are deleted by you.   
These processing operations are based on Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR. Our interest is the ongoing optimization and usability of our website.

 **6.     My Fonts**

My Fonts is a cookie from Monotype Image Holdings Inc. that helps us with implementing fonts on our website. You can find comprehensive information on how these cookies process your personal data (generally only your IP Address and time of access) at the following link: [www.monotype.com/legal/privacy-policy/web-font-tracking-privacy-policy/&nbsp](https://www.monotype.com/legal/privacy-policy/web-font-tracking-privacy-policy/&nbsp);  
These processing operations are based on Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR. Our interest is the ongoing optimization and usability of our website.

 **7.     Google Cookies & Analytics**

This website uses Google Cookies & Analytics. These are cookies managed by Google Inc. (“Google”) for the purpose of analysing internet and website usage, and often also for advertising. Personal data processed in this context is your IP address (which will entail your location data) and further information produced by your movements on the internet in connection with that IP address. 

This data is fully pseudonymised. The IP address sent by your browser as part of Google Analytics is not combined with other data held by Google. In some cases, the truncating of your IP address occurs so swiftly that no personal data is stored by Google for these purposes. This means in those circumstances, the information collected by Google is entirely anonymised. Some processing by Google will only occur in the European Union. For some cookies, the processing will occur on servers located in the United States. Safeguards for your personal data where this occurs are that Google Inc. is Privacy Shield certified, meaning your personal data is processed to a standard acceptable under EU expectations.

Below you will find information about the sort of Google cookies used by this website. You are able to manage the way Google uses your information and/or the way Google cookies track you on this site. All Google cookies preferences can be managed at the following link: [policies.google.com/technologies/managing](https://policies.google.com/technologies/managing?hl=en&nbsp);

Cookies used in this context on this site are:

a)   _  Google Analytics:_ Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google. Google uses this information on behalf of the website operator to evaluate the way you use the website, to collate reports on website activities and to provide the website operator other services related to website and Internet use.  
b)   _  Doubleclick:_ Doubleclick is an advertisement management and bidding service that streamlines advertisements. As a user, this means that cookies allow Google to serve ads based on previous visits to our or other websites on the Internet based on your movements.  
c)   _  GA Audiences: _GA Audiences is a Google cookie that is engaged based on your interaction with the website, generally if you frequent the website. 

By using our webpages, you agree to the processing of the data collected about you by Google in the manner described above. You can prevent the storage of such cookies by ensuring your settings are set accordingly in your internet browser, including by using the link provided above. Please note, your use of our website may be affected where you block or ban tracking cookies. If you would like further information about Google’s Privacy Policy, that information can be found here: [policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en.&nbsp);

These processing operations are based on Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR. Our interest is the ongoing optimization and usability of our website.

 **8.     External links and Plugins**

This page may offer external links and/or plugins, generally for social media. When you click on this, your personal data will be shared with the relevant external site. Once you leave this website, the processing of your personal data is no longer regulated by us nor governed by this Notice. Where you click on a social media plugin (indicated by the relevant symbol), personal data is gathered by that entity. It is generally your IP address, perhaps information about the directing site, and, where you remain automatically logged-in on your device to the social media site, they will collect information about your profile. Clicking on external links and plugins is entirely voluntary; therefore, if you do not wish for your personal data to be processed in this way, you do not have to click on these links. 

 **9.     Newsletter**

Where you register for our newsletter, and consent to this pursuant to Article 6(1)(a) of the GDPR, we will use your email address to regularly send you our newsletter and similar promotional materials. For the receipt of our newsletter, providing us with an email address is sufficient.

 _You can unsubscribe from receiving our newsletter at any time by clicking on the provided link sent with every newsletter communication. Alternatively, you can always send an unsubscribe request to marketing@cut-e.com._

 **INFORMATION FOR GENERAL PUBLIC, CUSTOMERS AND SUPPLIERS**

 **1\. Purpose and Legal Basis  **

Below you will find information regarding our processing of personal data from suppliers, customers and the general public. This information is intended for customers, suppliers and the general public who are natural persons and/or employees of customers and suppliers.

 **1.1 Contact & Customer Care  
Categories of Personal Data:** Contact details, HR details.  
 **Purpose of processing:** Initiate contact and maintain communications and provide assistance.   
 **Legal basis for our processing:** Where there is a contract in place between your entity and ours: Article 6(1)(b) ( _the provision of personal data is not required by law or by contract, however, without the personal data, the purpose cannot be achieved_ ). Where there is no contract in place between your entity and ours: Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is to make contact with you and maintain this line of communication.

 **1.2     Marketing  
Categories of Personal Data:** Contact details, HR details.  
 **Purpose of processing:** Send you marketing materials, technical information and/or legal updates.  
 **Legal basis for our processing:** Where your consent has been explicitly requested: Article 6(1)(a) ( _your consent can be withdrawn at any time with future effect_ ). Other: Article 6(1)(f) – our legitimate interest is to provide you with information relevant to our services in a marketing capacity.

 **2\. Recipients of your Personal Data**

We only share your personal data where necessary for the purpose of the processing.

Aon will be the primary recipient of your personal data. This includes Aon’s subsidiaries and affiliates.

 **Unaffiliated third parties:** We may share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties who perform administrative, marketing, professional or technological support functions for us.

 **Authoritative bodies:** Aon’s Assessment Solutions may be required to disclose personal information by law or legal process. 

 **2.     Transfer to third countries and/or international organisations**

Even if you are located in the European Union, personal data collected may be processed in a country where the adequacy of that countries data protection laws have not been approved by an adequacy decision of the European Commission. Where we transfer personal data in this manner, we will ensure that any such agreements involving the processing of your personal data will be concluded so that your personal information is protected to an acceptable EU standard under standard EU contractual clauses for the transfer of data, which provide you and your personal data with adequate safeguards. If you would like more information as to how we protect your personal data in these circumstances, please contact our Data Protection Officer with the contact details that we provided above.

 **3.     Storage of your Personal Data **

We only store your personal information for a period reasonable for our purposes of processing and/or for a period of time that is required of us by the law. We do not process your data any longer than we need to. 

If you would like more information about our retention periods, please contact our Data Protection Officer with the contact details that we provided above.

 **YOUR PERSONAL DATA RIGHTS**

 **1.     Your personal data rights**

We will always facilitate your requests when you exercise your rights over your personal data. Below you will find more information regarding these rights. 

When you make a request for your personal data, please specify in which form you wish to receive the information. If you do not specify this, we will respond to your request in the same form in which you made your request. We will make contact with you and attempt to resolve your request within a one month time frame. For manifestly unfounded or excessive requests, we are entitled to demand a reasonable fee or refuse the request.

Please contact gdpr@cut-e.com if you wish to exercise your rights or obtain more information.

 **1.1 Access (Article 15, GDPR):** You have the right to request confirmation as to whether we process your personal data. Where we process your personal data, you have the right to request access to your personal data.

 **1.2 Rectification (Article 16, GDPR):** You have the right to request that inaccurate or incomplete personal data processed by us is rectified or completed. Your right to do so can be exercised by providing a supplementary statement. Where we have disclosed your personal data to other recipients, we will, where possible, inform them of such correction and provide information as to these recipients where you so request.

 **1.3 Erasure (Article 17, GDPR):** You have the right to request the erasure of your personal data, where there is no legal exception for its retention. Please note that we are subjected to various legal storage requirements. Where we have disclosed your personal data to other recipients, we will, where possible, inform them of such correction and provide information as to these recipients where you so request.

 **1.4 Restriction of processing (Article 18, GDPR):** You have the right in certain instances to request the restriction of the processing of your personal data. Where we has disclosed your personal data to other recipients, we will, where possible, inform them of such correction and provide information as to these recipients where you so request.

 **1.5 Data Portability (Article 20, GDPR):** You may be entitled to request a copy of your personal data in a commonly used and machine readable format. This right includes the right to request us to transmit the personal data to another controller at your direction. This right is only available to you where the personal data has been provided by you, and is processed on the basis of consent or on the performance of a contract, or where the processing is carried out by automated means.

 **2.     Data Subject Rights: Objection**

 ** _Objection to our processing of your data (Article 21, GDPR)_  
Where your personal data is processed for the purpose of performing tasks carried out in the public interest (Article 6(1)(e)), for the purpose of legitimate interests of the controller (Article 6(1)(f)), for the purpose of direct marketing, and/or profiling (Article 21(2)), you are able, based on the grounds relating to your particular situation, to object to the processing of your personal data.**

 **3.     Complaints**

You always maintain the right to submit a complaint to the relevant supervisory authority regarding our processing of your personal data.

 **4.     Comments**

All comments relating to this Notice and/or regarding your personal data should be directed to gdpr@cut-e.com. 

If you would like a copy of this Notice, please contact our Data Protection Officer.
